I just launched my robotic arm for
我刚刚第一次启动了机器臂
the first time only to discover that it was swinging around loosely.
却发现它旋转时比较松弛
I challenged you to figure out why and I gave you a hint.
我要求你找出原因 并给出了提示
Assuming that you're up for the challenge,
假设你主动思考了
you might have seen the following warning line,
你可能已经看到了下面这条警告
"Controller Spawner couldn't find the expected controller manager ROS interface."
“Controller Spawner 无法找到预期的控制器管理器 ROS 接口”
I'm going to jump right to the punch line here.
我准备直接跳到这里的关键行
It turns out that we were missing a runtime dependency.
似乎缺失了运行时间依赖关系
ROS packages have two different types of dependencies;
ROS 包有两种类型的依赖：
build dependencies, and run dependencies.
版本依赖和运行依赖
You fix the first build dependency by using a combination of
首先可以修复版本依赖 使用
Google search and apt-get to install the ROS kinetic controller manager package.
谷歌搜索和 apt-get 安装 ROS kinetic 控制器管理器包
Doing this allowed the package to build without complaints but when you
这样可以保证包构造更加简单 不会引发抱怨
ran it you got a warning and things didn't function as expected.
但运行包时 会收到警告 告诉你功能未达预期
This is where the rosdep tool comes in handy.
这时候 rosdep 工具就派上用场了
The rosdep tool will check for a packages missing dependencies,
Rosdep 工具会检查包有无缺失的依赖关系
download them and install them.
然后现在并安装
Let's go ahead and take a look at
我们来看看
the dependencies that were missing from the simple_arm package.
Simple_arm 包中缺失的依赖关系
Let's first go ahead and kill Gazebo and all of the running nodes.
首先 我们关闭 Gazebo 和所有运行的节点
You can do so by entering Ctrl C in the ROS Master console window.
你可以在 ROS 主控制台窗口中输入 Ctrl C 完成该操作
Now in the root of your catkin workspace with setup, ".Bash source."
现在 在你带设置的 catkin 工作空间中的根目录下 .bash source
You're going to want to type the command "rosdep
你需要键入命令 rosdep
check," and then the name of your package.
check 然后是包的名称
Here it's, "simple_arm," and then hit enter.
这里是 simple_arm 然后点击回车键
And there you have it, a list of
这里 我们得到了
the system dependencies that are missing and where to get them.
缺失的系统依赖关系列表 以及下载地址
Now we could have just use apt-get to install these but I'm going to show you a trick.
现在 我们可以使用 apt-get 来安装这些依赖关系 但还有个简便方法
You can simply let rosdep do it.
你可以使用 rosdep 操作
To make rosdep install packages,
要让 rospep 安装包
invoke the following command from the root of the catkin workspace.
你需要从 catkin 工作空间的根目录下运行下列命令
Rosdep Install -I simple_arm, and then hit enter.
Rosdep Install -I simple_arm 然后点击回车
The script will then install the missing Debian packages and there you have it.
然后 脚本会安装缺失的 Debian 包 搞定
Now, when you launch the simple_arm package everything should be operating as expected.
现在 当你启动 simple_arm 包的时候 一切都会和预期的一样
The joint controller, now that it's actually on your system,
联合控制器现在应该已经在系统中了
will be loaded and the arm will no longer swing around loosely. There we go.
它会被加载 并且机器臂不会再松散地晃动 就这样
Gazebo has been launched and as you can see the arm is rigid.
Gazebo 已经启动 你可以看到 机器臂非常牢靠
With all packages properly installed,
所有包都正确安装后
you will now learn more about ROS packages in
你现在可以进一步了解 ROS 包
preparation for writing your own nodes in the next lesson.
为下一堂课的节点编写做好准备了